Joey Chiao-Yin Hsiao

jcyhsiao@umich.edu • +1 (734) 730-0963 • http://joeyhsiao.info 4365 N. Quad, 105 S. State St., Ann Arbor, MI 48109, USA

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests are Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), Computer-Supported Cooperative Work (CSCW), and Social Computing. My current topic is focused on how location-based social applications, such as people-nearby applications, hybrid community applications, sharing economy applications, can support newcomers in adapting to a new environment.

EDUCATION

University of Michigan

Doctoral Candidate in Information

Advisor: Dr. Tawanna R. Dillahunt

National Taiwan University
M.S. in Computer Science

Carnegie Mellon University (Silicon Valley Campus)

Advisor: Dr. Jane Yung-Jen Hsu

Visiting Scholar

Advisor: Dr. Ted Selker National Taiwan University

B.S. in Computer Science

Ann Arbor, MI, USA

2015/09 – present

Taipei, Taiwan 2010/09 - 2013/06

Moffett Field, CA, USA

2012/07 - 2012/09

Taipei, Taiwan 2006/09 – 2010/06

PUBLICATIONS

Conference Proceeding Papers

- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Moser, C., Schoenebeck, S., and Dillahunt, T. R. (2018). The Role of Demographics, Trust, Computer Self-efficacy, and Ease of Use in the Sharing Economy. In *Proc. of the 1st ACM SIGCAS Conference on Computing and Sustainable Societies (COMPASS '18)*, Article 37 (Presenter).
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., and Dillahunt, T. R. (2017). People-Nearby Applications: How Newcomers Move Their Relationships Offline and Develop Social and Cultural Capital. In *Proc. of the 2017 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW '17)*, 26-40 (acceptance rate: 33%; Presenter).
- Rajan, R., **Hsiao**, **J. C.-Y.**, Lahoti, D., and Selker, T. (2013). "Roger that!" The Value of Adding Social Feedback in Audio-mediated Communications. In *Proc. of IFIP TC.13 International Conference on Human-Computer Interaction 2013 (INTERACT '13*), 471-488 (acceptance rate: 31%).
- Tsai, W.-C., **Hsiao, J. C.-Y.**, Lee, H.-C., Huang, C.-H., Hu, J.-C., Liang, R.-H., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2013). Designing a Reminiscence Aid in Personal Soundscape. In *Proc. of International Association of Societies of Design Research 2013 (IASDR '13*), 5150-5160.

Posters, Workshop Papers, and Presentations

- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Dillahunt, T. R. (2017) Detecting Life Changes: Increasing Opportunities to Benefit from People-Nearby Applications. In Proc. of *The ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstract 2017 (CHI EA '17)*, 1700 1707 (Presenter).
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Pan, M.-H., Wang, H.-C., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2015) Let's Solve It Together: Introducing Crowd Workers to Friendsourcing for Improving Creative Design. Presented at *The Taiwan Computer-Human Interaction Workshop 2015 (Tai-CHI '15)* (Presenter).
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Pan, M.-H., Wang, H.-C., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2015). The Price of the Priceless: Understanding Estimated Costs of Work in Friendsourcing. In *The ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstract 2015 (CHI EA '15)*, 1893-1898 (Presenter).
- Tsai, W.-C., Lee, H.-C., **Hsiao, J. C.-Y.**, Liang, R.-H., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2013). Framing Design of Reminiscence Aids with Transactive Memory Theory. In *The ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstract 2013 (CHI EA '13)*, 331-336.

Posters, Workshop Papers, and Presentations (Cont.)

- Tsai, W.-C., Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Lee, H.-C., Huang, C.-H., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2012). In Search of Lost Sounds: Designing a Reminiscence Aid in Everyday Soundscape. Presented at The ACM conference on Designing Interactive Systems 2012 (DIS '12).
- Hsiao, J. C.-Y., Jih, W.-R., and Hsu, Y.-J. (2012). Recognizing Continuous Social Engagement Level in Dyadic Conversation by Using Turn-taking and Speech Emotion Patterns. Presented at AAAI '12 Activity Context Representation Workshop (ACR '12) (Presenter).

Unpublished Theses and Technical Reports

• Hsiao, J. C.-Y. (2012). Assessing Engagement in Conversation by Hierarchically Decomposing Emotion and Interaction. Master's Thesis, Dept. of Computer Science and Information Engineering (CSIE), Natl. Taiwan Univ.

HONOR

Dept. CSIE, Natl. Taiwan Univ.

Taipei, Taiwan

Graduation Representative

2012

Was chosen as the recognized master's student for leadership and active participation in student affairs of the department

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Social Innovations Group, School of Information, Univ. of Michigan

Ann Arbor, MI, USA

2015/09 - present

Supported Dr. Dillahunt and research of the Social Innovations Group (SIG), which is focused on designing technologies to help low-resourced populations seek employment and education (Advisor: Dr. Tawanna R. Dillahunt)

UX Team, Intel-NTU IoX Center

Taipei, Taiwan

Workshop Organizer

Research Assistant

2015/03 - 2015/05

Organized the collaborative workshop on design thinking of Stanford d.school and National Taiwan University IoX Center

Research Assistant

2014/07 - 2015/07

Carried out research on user experience and natural user interface under smart environment as the only M.S. member in the team (Advisor: Dr. Bing-Yu Chen)

Collaborative & Social Computing Lab, Dept. CS, Natl. Tsing-Hua Univ.

Hsinchu, Taiwan

Collaborative Researcher

2014/07 - 2015/07

Led a project on friendsourcing, aiming to understand how social capital works when a SNS user requests resources on her/his own social network (Advisor: Dr. Hao-Chuan Wang)

Taiwan Army (Mandatory Military Service)

Taichung, Taiwan

Company Chief Consultant (Second Lieutenant)

2013/08 - 2014/07

Handled psychological consulting, human resources management, and welfare of a military company with 40+ members

Intelligent Agents Lab, Dept. CSIE, Natl. Taiwan Univ.

Taipei, Taiwan

System Administrator

2011/03 - 2013/07

Managed devices and web services for 30+ lab members

PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

Academic Events & Activities

ACM MobileHCI 2019 2017/09 - Present

Student Volunteer Chair

TaiCHI 2015 2015/01 - 2015/07

Organizing Committee

OpenHCI Workshop 2014 (student-organized workshop on HCI in Taiwan) 2014/01 - 2014/07

Steering Committee

OpenHCI Workshop 2013 2013/01 - 2013/07

Program Chair

OpenHCI Workshop 2011 Human Resource Manager 2011/01 - 2011/07

Social Events & Activities

Univ. of Michigan, School of Information Doctoral Committee Representative Start 2018/09

Annual Taiwan Night at CHI Organizing Committee 2015 - 2018

Reviewer

ACM CHI 2017, 2018 ACM CSCW 2017, 2018 ACM MobileHCI 2018

Conference Student Volunteer

ACM COMPASS 2018 ACM CSCW 2017

ACM TEI 2017

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant/Graduate Student Instructor

School of Information, Univ. of Michigan Winter 2018

SI-622: Usability Testing Instructor: Prof. Joyojeet Pal

School of Information, Univ. of Michigan Fall 2017

SI-501: Textual Inquiry

Instructor: Prof. Kentaro Toyama

 $Dept.\ CSIE,\ Natl.\ Taiwan\ Univ.\ {\mathcal E}$

Dept. Design, Natl. Taiwan Univ. of Tech. and Sci. 2013/02 – 2013/06

Advanced Human-Computer Interface/User-Oriented Innovation Design

Instructor: Prof. Hsien-Hui Tang & Prof. Mike Y. Chen

Dept. CSIE, Natl. Taiwan Univ. 2010/09 - 2011/01

Introduction to Computer Science Instructor: Prof. Jane Yung-Jen Hsu

Student Team Coach

OpenHCI Workshop 2011 2011/07

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Volunteer for Autism
StarRain Service Association for Autism
2008/02 - 2013/06